Guide to Rice University: One Hundred Years in Pictures, manuscripts and publishing records, 2009-2014, UA 319 UA 319
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University: One Hundred Years in Pictures, manuscripts and publishing records
2009-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice Historical Society
UA 319
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Committee records, manuscript drafts, print and digital images, and reviews document the process undertaken by the Rice Historical Society to organize and have published: Rice University: One Hundred Years in Pictures.
Biographical / Historical
Rice University, a private, independent, coeducational university in Houston, opened in 1912 as the William Marsh Rice Institute. It was chartered in 1891 by former Houston merchant William Marsh Rice with a $200,000 interest-bearing note payable to the Rice Institute upon his death.
In 2009, the Rice Historical Society began a project to publish a book commemorating the upcoming centennial of the founding of Rice University. Rice University: One Hundred Years in Pictures was published by Texas A & M University Press in September 2012. The book includes more than 300 photographs that tell the story of a century of student life, a world-famous faculty, and news-making events at Rice.
Excerpted from: https://tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/kbr05
Scope and Contents
Committee records, manuscript collections, print and digital images, and book reviews document the process undertaken by the Rice Historical Society to complete the publication of Rice University: One Hundred Years in Pictures. Of particular interests are the versions of the manuscripts through the editing process and digital copies of images used, and not used, in the book.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were transferred to Woodson from the Rice Historical Society.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Rice University -- History; Photography
Document Types
digital images; compact discs; manuscripts (document genre)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice Historical Society
- Series I: Images & Artwork, 2010-2013
  - Image Numbering & Captions, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Text & Images (2 discs), 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Image Captions, 2011-05-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Images - Woodson Numbers & Captions, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Original Artwork & Other Materials (10 discs), 2010-2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II: Manuscript Drafts, n.d.
  - Early Manuscript Drafts (annotated), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annotated Manuscript Draft, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Later Annotated Draft, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Later Annotated Draft, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annotated Draft, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annotated Draft with Images, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Texas A&M Press First Proof, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series III: Project Organization and Implementation, 2009-2012
  - Rice Pictorial History - Copyediting, 2018-09-03 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - RHS Centennial Book Committee, 2009-2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript Reviews, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Book Jacket, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Publicity, 2013-2014
  - Book Reviews, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Publicity, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - PowerPoint Presentation (incl. flashdrive), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)